Challenges

Challenges are a feature unique to Ultra Skirmish.  Those familiar with RPGs however will quickly recognise that they are quests with various goals.  Challenges are available in the Drop Portal Store and cost a small amount of soda.  Players purchase these challenges and must fulfil the goals to get the Challenge reward (dog tags).

A couple things about Challenges:

- You may only have one active Challenge at a time.

- You may not complete the same Challenge twice.

- To see your objectives, right click on the Challenge item that is given to you when you start the Challenge, and check out the info.

- For Timed challenges there are two types of goals - complete the challenge in X amount of total time or complete the same task several times, always within a set amount of time.  When a challenge's name is "10 Kills in 10 Minutes" this means you must get 10 kills in 10 minutes total.  If the name is "10 Kills per 1 Minute" this means you must get 1 kill every minute until you have 10 kills total.  Failing to get a second kill within a minute after getting your first kill (and so on) results in failure.

- Challenges always give you challenge items.  These are timer items, stat items, or related important items.  You cannot drop or sell these items.

- When you spec or change arenas (technically it happens when you unspec) you lose your current challenge and any progress you have made towards your goal.

- As of implementation, challenges do not have intrinsic rewards.  This will come when there are an appropriate number of working challenges available to everyone.

The Challenges (as of 5/9/9):

5 Kill Streak: Get 5 kills in a row.  When you get a kill your Kill Streak increases and when you die your Kill Streak stat resets to 0.  When you achieve 5 consecutive kills you get the reward.  This challenge cannot be failed.

10 Kills per 2 Minutes: You are given a two minute timer.  You must get a kill before this two minute timer runs out.  If you do get a kill, your timer is reset and you must get another kill, until you have 10 kills total.  You fail the challenge if you don't manage to get a kill in any given two minute allotment.

10 Kills in 10 Minutes: You are given a ten minute timer.  You must get 10 kills before this ten minute timer runs out.  You fail the challenge if you don't manage to get 10 kills in the ten minute allotment.

10 Kills to 3 Death Ratio: You must get 10 Kills without dying more than 3 times, thus achieving a 10:3 Kill:Death Ratio.